HUSEYIN KARTAL - IT INFASTRUICTURE & SYSTEM CONSULTANT (VMWARE VEXPERT)

Address: London Mobile: +44 7555 816 227

Huseyin.kartal@live.com, huseyinkartal.tr@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kartalhuseyin

Hi Dear Sir/Madam,

I have 10-years' experience of the IT industry. I had complete a lot of difficult and complex projects. (Migrations, Upgrades, Installations), Also I have great SysOps management skills. I am experienced in Microsoft, HP, Dell, IBM, Fujitsu, VMware had gain great experience of brands such as.

I am a passionate IT professional who loves to work.

EXPERIENCE

05.2019

IT CONTRACTOR FW & NETWORK ENGINEER, CO-OP SUPER MARKET RETAILS / MIDLANDS

Giving network & firewall consultancy for network transition project, Replacing Firewall and Switches. Install, Manage, Migration Cisco Meraki Switches and Meraki Firewalls re-design Network cabinets.

11.2018 - 05.2019

IT CONTRACTOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR, VIX TECHNOLOGY / CAMBRIDGE SCIENCE PARK

Providing consultancy in the Vix technology the below subjects and manage two separate Datacenter London based (disaster & production DC), Supporting in World based branches, France, Sweden, New Zealand, Australia.

Managing Microsoft Server issues

Managing Cisco ASA Firewall

Managing Juniper Firewall

Managing Veeam Backup & Replication Backup strategy

Managing Vmware Virtualization structure

Managing Active Directory issues

Managing HP C7000 Blade & on physical blade servers.

Managing HP 3PAR & Qnap NAS Storage's

Business As Usual Daily processes

01.2015 - 09.2018

SR. SYSTEM ENGINEER, MATRIS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES

I worked as a system & pre sales engineer at this firm. I am working on pre-sales customer needs determination, infrastructure system design and architecture and after-sales installation.

Following Topics Design, Installation, Maintenance, Upgrade, Troubleshooting Operations.

- VMware, Hyper-V, Citrix Xen App, Citrix Xen Desktop
- NetApp FAS, E-series, Dell EqualLogic, Vmware VSAN, HP (HPE) EVA, MSA2000, 3PAR, EMC
- Sophos, FortiGate firewalls.
- AWS, Azure Virtual Machines.
- Zerto Disaster Recovery Solution.
- Veeam Backup & Replication, Arcserve UDP
- Microsoft Deployment Tool OS Deployment W7, W8,W10

- Microsoft Win. Server 2003, 2008, 2012,2016.
- MS Office 365
- Dell, HP, IBM Servers
- Microsoft Active Directory
- Microsoft Exchange 2003 >2016
- Linux Redhat, Centos Installation & Management
- SCCM Update & OS Deployment Inventory Management.

2013 - 2015

SYSTEM DEVELOPMENT EXPERT, BILGISISTEMLERI SAN.DIS.TIC. LTD

I worked as a system development expert at this firm. I Completed many virtualization, security, infrastructure, Microsoft (upgrade, migration and troubleshooting) projects.

- VMware Hyper-V
- Hpe EVA, MSA, 3PAR Storage
- Cyberoam, FortiGate firewalls.
- Microsoft Windows Server 2003, 2008, 2012,2016.
- Veeam Backup & Replication, NetBackup

- Microsoft Active Directory
- Microsoft Exchange 2003 >2013
- Linux Redhat, Centos Installation & Management.
- McAfee ePolicy Orchestrator
- HPE DI380, DL580, Blade C7000, C3000

2010 - 2012

INFORMATION SECURITY EXPERT, HELIUM INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES

It is the distributor of Kaspersky, TrendMicro, Checkpoint products which are the leading solutions of Helium Information Security products which have branches in Istanbul, Izmir, Ankara, Bursa and Trabzon.

- I have been tasked with positioning and implementing the products that are sold to the Enterprise and VIP customers, making migration transactions and providing remote and onsite support Services.
- I gave workshops and trainings to Helium Inf. Tech. dealers.
- I worked with the Business Development Manager in the process of developing Network and System Security projects and worked at the enterprise level before and after sales.

2007 - 2009

INFORMATION SYSTEMS AUDITOR, YILDIZ HOLDING ÜLKER (FORTECH)

Ulker / Yıldız holding structure configured within the WAN area which was taken over in the transition to
a Windows domain with additional domain controller, Exchange 2003 mailbox setup and processing
information to the personnel the necessary training in the region, I took part in the project

EDUCATION

INTERNET & NETWORK TECH, SAKARYA UNIVERSITY

Sakarya University | Informatics Institute, Internet and Network Technologies (Open Education)

HIGH SCHOOL

Pendik High School

CORE SKILLS

- Virtualization; VMware vSphere (ESXI), VCenter, VSAN,
 Hyper-V Clustering.
- Microsoft Active Directory Administration (2003>2016)
 GPO, FSMO, ADFS ..
- Microsoft Exchange 2003,2007,2010,2013,2016
- Microsoft Windows Servers 2003,2008,2012,2016
- Microsoft Services DNS, DHCP, IIS, DFS, GPO,
- Microsoft Windows Xp, Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 10 Operating Systems
- Microsoft SCCM, SCVMM, MDT, USDT
- Microsoft Office, Microsoft Visio
- Infrastructure Backup Appliance; EMC Datadomain, HPE StoreOnce, Fujitsu CS800.
- Microsoft Azure VM, Microsoft Azure AD, Microsoft Azure Storage.
- AWS Amazon Web Services EC2, S3, VPC, Disaster Recovery for Zerto

- Microsoft Office 365, DirSync, AADSync
- Microsoft SQL; Installing, Clustering, Backup Operations
- Infrastructure Server; HP(HPE), Dell, IBM (Lenovo),
 Fujitsu, Rackmount and Blade Chassis.
- Infrastructure Storage; EMC NetApp FAS E-Series, HP (HPE) EVA, HP 3PAR, MSA-P 2000, Lefthand FC, FcOE, SAS, ISCSI, NFS, CIFS Protocols, DataOntap, Ontap, Cdot, 7mode Operations System
- Security; Trend Micro, McAfee, Sophos, Symantec, FortiGate Firewall, Antivirus, Antispam.
- Network, Basic Networking Switching VLAN, TCP/IP, TCP/UDP, LAN WAN WLAN, Wireless, Access Points.
- Backup; Veeam Backup & Replication, Arcserve UDP,
 Zerto Disaster Recovery, Veritas Backup Exec, Acronis
- Linux: CentOS, Ubuntu, Fedora, Suse, RedHat Installation & Management.

CERTIFICATES

- VMware vEXPERT 2019
- VMware Certified Professional 6.5 Data Center Virtualization
- NCDA Netapp Clustered Data ONTAP Administration
- MCSE Microsoft Certified Systems Engineer: Windows Server 2003
- MCTS Microsoft® Certified Technology Specialist: Microsoft ISA) Server 2006, Configuration
- MCSA Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator: Windows Server 2003
- MCP Microsoft Certified Professional: Microsoft Certified Professional
- MCTS Microsoft® Certified Technology Specialist: Windows 7, Configuration
- MCSE Microsoft® Certified Solutions Expert: Productivity 2016
- MCSA Microsoft® Certified Solutions Associate: Windows Server 2016
- MCSE Microsoft® Certified Solutions Expert: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure
- Microsoft Specialist: Windows 7, Configuring
- MCSE Microsoft® Certified Solutions Expert: Server Infrastructure
- Microsoft® Certified Solutions Associate: Windows Server 2012
- Sophos XG Firewall Engineer
- Arcserve UDP Backup Engineer.
- McAfee ePolicy Orchestrator® Product Specialist
- TCSE Trend Micro Certified Security Expert
- Trend Micro Office Scan (OSCE) 10.5 TCSP

SEMINAR & COURSES

- NetApp Clustered Data Ontap Administration and Data Protection
- NetApp FAS storage series, Installing, management and upgrade, product training.
- Hewlett Packard Enterprise 3PAR Storage Technologies, Installing, Management and Troubleshooting
- Sophos Security- Sophos XG- Firewall Engineering
- Fortinet Firewall Installing, Management and Troubleshooting.
- Amazon Web Services Technical Essentials
- VMware vSphere 4x 5x Training VMware Esxi and vSphere Installing and management training.
- Cisco CCNA Training -Switching, Addressing, Routing, Network Security, Troubleshooting, WAN technologies
- Microsoft MCSE Training Server 2003/2008 Family Installing, Management, Roles Installing Management and Troubleshooting.

PROJECTS

PRIVATE SECTOR UK - AZURE SERVICE & VM MIGRATION - REFERENCE AVAILABLE

Responsibility in this role; Design & Preparing Azure Network, Design & Preparing Azure Site Recovery for VM migration, Azure AD sync.

- Migrated 20 VM to Azure North Europe Datacenter.
- Created Azure VM Backup policy's group by group.
- Created Azure VPN on the On prem Datacenter
- Created Azure Identity and Access Management
- Configured Azure File Services and Synchronization On prem File Server.

PRIVATE SECTOR UK – WINDOWS 10 MIGRATION PROJECT- REFERENCE AVAILABLE

Responsibility in this role; Deployment Engineer, Design MDT Server, Create & Deploy OS image.

In This Project, was migrated the Operating systems with MDT Windows 7, Windows 8 etc. Migration to Windows 10 for 400 Client.

- Creating Operating System Windows 10 Deployment Image.
- Creating Driver packages
- Creating Application Deployments Office 365.
- User State Migration Tool (USMT) user profile backup and restore process,

PRIVATE SECTOR UK – MIGRATION ON PREMISE EXCHANGE 2010 TO OFFICE 365 - REFERENCE AVAILABLE

Responsibility in this role: This company has 100 more users Identify Office 365 Requirements, Design Migration steps, determine license requirements, Deploying and managing migration.

- Design cutover migration scenario.
- Azure AD Connect configuration
- Move User mailbox
- License Management.
- Create documentation for reidentify client.
- Identify Relay settings for peripheral devices.

MEDICINE SECTOR -- DATACENTER UPGRADE DISASTER RECOVERY CENTER PROJECT

Responsibility in this role; Design, Install, Maintain Hardware & Software, Managing Project In This Project, many services and roles are upgraded and migrated as indicated below

- 2x VMware Esxi node Dell R730 installation, Configuration.
- 1x Physical Dell R530 Vcenter & Veeam Backup Server.
- 1x Physical Dell R430 Domain Controller.
- Netapp FAS 2552 SAN Storage Installation, Configuration and Data migration from Netapp FAS 2040.
- Exchange 2003 migration to Exchange 2010 SP3.
- Active directory Migration to Server 2012 R2.
- Veeam Backup and Replication with Backup and Replication structure installation and Configuration
- WSUS Configuration, implementation

MLP CARE (MEDICAL PARK HOSPITALS GROUP)

Responsibility in this role; Design, Install, Maintain Hardware & Software, Managing Project

- HPE 3PAR 8400 HPE installation, configuration management.
- Data migration from HPE EVA 8000 to HPE 3PAR
- 10 nodes Hyper-V Cluster Management.
- McAfee EPO installation, administration, Configuration (virus scanning enterprise) 10x group of hospitals.
- Exchange 2010 4-node CasArray & 4 Node Mailbox Server 9000x user management.

MEDICINE SECTOR- DATA CENTER UPGRADE PROJECT

Responsibility in this role; Design, Install, Maintain Hardware & Software, Managing Project

- Active Directory, DNS, DHCP Server 2003 Migration to Server 2012 R2.
- Exchange 2007 migration to Exchange 2013
- Exchange 2013 on Install McAfee E-mail Security for Microsoft Exchange.
- McAfee E-Policy Orchestrator (EPO) Virus Scan Enterprise installation, Configuration and management.
- Netapp FAS 8020 SAN Storage installation, Configuration and management.

METAL INDUSTRY - DATA CENTER UPGRADING HARDWARE & SOFTWARE PROJECT.

Responsibility in this role; Design, Install, Maintain Hardware & Software, Managing Project Data Center Upgrading Hardware and Software Project.

- Exchange 2003 Migration to Exchange 2013.
- Active Directory Server 2003 Migration to Server 2012 R2
- Installing Symantec Bright Mail on Exchange 2013.
- Arcserve UDP Backup Solution Installing and configuring.
- 4x Dell R530 Server Installing and Configuring.

PRIVATE SECTOR - DATACENTER UPGRADE & DISASTER RECOVERY SITE CREATION

Responsibility in this role; Design, Install, Maintain Hardware & Software, Managing Project

- Vmware Vsphere Vcenter & Esxi host version Upgrade from 5.5 to 6.5
- Add existing Esxi farm new 4x Dell R730 Servers.
- Netapp FAS 8020 SAN Storage installation, Configuration and management.

- Brocade 300 SAN Switch Configuration & Management
- Veeam Backup & Replication (Lan Free) backup strategy creation
- Zerto Disaster Recovery Solution Installation & Management (Istanbul Production DC Zenium Replicated more than 100 servers to Ankara Disaster site DC Super Online.

•

PUBLIC SECTOR UNIVERSITY - DISTANCE UNIVERSIY DATACENTER INSTALLATION, VIRTUALIZATION STRUCTURE

Responsibility in this role; Design, Install, Maintain Hardware & Software, Managing Project

- 5 HPE DL380 G8 Server Installation.
- Hyper-V Cluster System Installation, Configuration
- HPE MSA 2040 Storage Installation, Configuration
- 2x HPE Store Easy NAS Storage Installation, Configuration.

REFERENCES

Available on request (UK Reference)